Remember we talked about hard coded values like these which are never recommended because
as I said they make your program or applications one dimensional rather we should take in
always use an input from runtime and there are few ways to do it in Java but I'll just
keep it simple for you I'll just walk you through the most popular way of doing that
and that is through the scanner class the inbox scanner class let's try to do that so
I'll do is let me quickly go on and even create a new class here I'll just right click
on the package and say new Java class more about packages in a little video but for now
let's just call it user input right enter let me again maximize the font for you put it
full screen will again have the mean method right at this time I'll just say just
get it the scanner class now the scanner class the beauty of intelligent can you start
typing and it just gives you the intelligence it says that this class is a Java dot
util package that means you need to import it but you don't need to do the heavy lifting
just hit enter and intelligent put in the input for you now import is the keyword import
is used to import classes in Java like from Java to util this is the super package the
sub package and this is the class again see S isn't capitals that is cable case should
be a class and then you hover on this it just gives you the description about this class
as well that tells you a simple text scanner right and this is what we're using I'll just
call it variable as scan I'll say new scanner and here because we want to take user input
from runtime that's why I say system dot end I say I don't have to do it from any file right
but from console runtime that's where system dot end comes in and then I'll ask the user
to enter a number or a couple of numbers and I'll just say for example a sound this time I'll
say enter another and the user I'll just say int let's call it value and you'll say scan dot next
see now in scan and there are lots of utility methods right if you want to take a string
from user runtime there is next and there is next line if you want to take a int there is next
int if you want to take a bite there is next bite next short next Boolean double and so on a lot
of utility myths out there but for now we're just interested in taking integer see it has the return
type of int and we're taking it in a variable of value that is a type int the compiler is happy
and for now I'll just printed back I'll just say you entered the value and I'll just concatenated
value and let's go on and check this so what happens is when the user gets this scan dot next line
the cursor just keeps on blinking the console just pauses until the user enters something and hits
enter so I'll just say it could be like see enter number it has stopped for a paused for us
waiting for us to enter any number and I'll say one two eight six and it says you entered the value
as one two eight six right so that is the simplest way of taking a value from runtime even if
you want to take a string I'll just comment this out control slash remember and then you'll say
a south I'll say enter unit let's say we want to take a name of a user and I'll just go on and
say this time this variable value variable type is string I'll just say user name again in
camel case remember because you small in capital that's how we declare variables and I'll just say
scan dot next line because we want to take the next line as well and I'll just say a south
let's say welcome username we're just printing it apart that's just simplified stop I'll just
go on and hit run it says enter your name and I'll say believe say it's welcome well it you hit
it the next time that's the multi-dimensional nature of our program now it's not hard coded I'll just
say enter your name and you'll just see for example sonna and says welcome sonna right on your screen
so that is and then try your hand son with taking doubles by its bullions shorts you have all
those utility methods in the scanning class and a point here with integers is that is when you say
next int right and let's say after this you have to take another string or another integer so
make sure you do a empty scan dot next line because what happens with integers is next int doesn't
have the capability to take the next line as well so what happens is it doesn't take it just puts
the value here and if you don't put it then you are in problems right then whatever you're doing
next would just take the next line but not the actual value so whenever you're taking integers and
after that you're taking any strings or any any other values just do an empty next line that just
absorbs the next line that is the slash and that's it otherwise pretty straightforward stuff
that's how you scan to take user input from runtime to make your programs dynamic in nature